EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

ABOUT ME

After serving ten years with the Wisconsin Army National Guard while earning a degree in Graphic Design and Marketing, I decided to move to Minneapolis and pursue my career in design. Now in Seattle, I look forward to continuing my journey in all things design.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SLALOM: EXPERIENCE DESIGNER: APRIL 2019 - PRESENT

Lead projects in user-centered design solutions, define requirements for web and mobile products, work with development teams and project leadership to define and refine scope, produce wireframes, user flows, IA diagrams and prototypes for web and mobile experiences, manage design assets, and review UI for proper implementation.

PUSH INTERACTIVE: LEAD UX/UI DESIGNER: DECEMBER 2017 - APRIL 2019

Research, strategize and manage projects, providing leadership and direction to our team to innovate and stay on top of industry trends. At the same time I collaborate with my dev team to help create user-centered interactive designs that stress empathy to the user experience, strive for web standards, and maintain attention to detail.

THINKSEM: CREATIVE DIRECTOR: MAY 2011 - NOVEMBER 2017

Curate current and new design services, manage strategic business development and goals, conduct client consultation and strategy, as well as manage, implement, and continually improve all design/development capabilities. Lead an agile design team that concentrates on maintaining web standards (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript), using analytics to improve the user experience, content strategy, site performance, and accessibility, and using client/team feedback in combination with critical thinking to create the most optimized web experience possible. Created a WordPress-based theme store that introduced highly valuable capabilities and a new source of revenue for the agency.

THE LACEK GROUP: FRONT-END DEVELOPER: DECEMBER 2010 - MAY 2011

Created microsites, single page sites, and HTML emails for clients such as American Airlines and Enterprise Rent-A-Car with a cohesive interactive design team. Worked extensively with testing software (Litmus) to provide support for a multitude of email clients. Was victorious in many nerf-gun battles.

GLOBE UNIVERSITY: WEB DESIGNER: NOVEMBER 2009 - DECEMBER 2010

Designed, developed, and maintained university websites in collaboration with design and IT teams. Created wireframes and mock-ups to communicate with internal stakeholders ensuring visual designs met brand and usability standards. Worked in .NET environment to bring front-end designs into Sitefinity CMS.

LANCER HOSPITALITY: GRAPHIC DESIGNER: MAY 2008 - NOVEMBER 2009

Collaborated with the art director in a fast-paced environment to create print designs including pamphlets, posters, menus, etc. Showed decisiveness and the ability to be a self-starter by pitching, creating, and maintaining connected web experiences for online properties that included a restaurant, child care dining, and ongoing events. Used Adobe tools such as Illustrator, InDesign, and Dreamweaver.

BOOZ ALLEN HAMILTON: GRAPHIC DESIGNER (PAID INTERNSHIP): JUNE 2007 - DECEMBER 2007

Worked directly with internal stakeholders to provide print and digital design deliverables such as posters, internal documentation, and SharePoint site updates. Designed using Adobe design tools such as Photoshop, Illustrator, and InDesign.

WISCONSIN ARMY NATIONAL GUARD: SERGEANT: AUGUST 1998 - AUGUST 2008

Ultimately worked in a leadership role as part of several units over the course of my time with the military. Roles included Motor Transport Operator (88M) and Automated Logistical Specialist (92A). Served year-long tour in Operation Iraqi Freedom in support role transporting equipment and personnel from various locations in Iraq back to base in Kuwait.

SKILL SET

- Project/Client Consultation
- · Brand Identity
- User Experience Design
- Information Architecture
- · Responsive Website Design
- · Custom Wordpress Development
- Strive for Accessibility
- Cross Browser Support/Device Testing
- Prototypes
- Confident
- · Open to Critical Feedback

SOME TOOLS I USE

- Miro
- Balsamiq
- Sketch
- InVision
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Sublime Text (HTML5/CSS3(SASS))
- CodeKit
- BrowserStack
- Hotjar

EDUCATION/ACHIEVEMENTS

WINONA STATE UNIVERSITY

BA in Graphic Design w/minor in Marketing

CONTINUED EDUCATION

- Treehouse courses
- CSS Tricks tips/tutorials
- A List Apart
- InVision Blog

MILITARY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Commandant's Honor List
- · Army Achievement Medal
- · Overseas Service Ribbon